Guide to the John Edgar Coover Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John Edgar Coover papers
1907-1938
SC0371
Coover, John Edgar, 1872-1938.
0.75 Linear feet
Papers include Coover's correspondence with David Starr Jordan, Ray Lyman Wilbur, and the Board of Trustees, 1913-1936, concerning his psychic research and his annual reports to the University president, with several letters pertaining to the Australian medium Charles Bailey; typescript "Report on Experimentation upon the Transfer of Improved Conditions of Attention," 1910-11; typescript of his doctoral thesis, "Formal Discipline from the Standpoint of Experimental Psychology," 1912; reprints of Coover's articles on psychic research and his "Notescript," a form of shorthand, 1913-ca. 1936; and miscellaneous clippings, 1912-1938. Also included is a diary kept by his wife Margaret E. Coover, 1907-1915, concerning social affairs, club activities, domestic life, and Coover's positions.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of Psychology at Stanford and Thomas Welton Stanford Fellow in Psychic Research, 1910-1937.
Description of the Collection
Papers include Coover's correspondence with David Starr Jordan, Ray Lyman Wilbur, and the Board of Trustees, 1913-1936, concerning his psychic research and his annual reports to the University president, with several letters pertaining to the Australian medium Charles Bailey; typescript "Report on Experimentation upon the Transfer of Improved Conditions of Attention," 1910-11; typescript of his doctoral thesis, "Formal Discipline from the Standpoint of Experimental Psychology," 1912; reprints of Coover's articles on psychic research and his "Notescript," a form of shorthand, 1913-ca. 1936; and miscellaneous clippings, 1912-1938. Also included is a diary kept by his wife Margaret E. Coover, 1907-1915, concerning social affairs, club activities, domestic life, and Coover's positions.
Access Terms
Bailey, Charles.; Coover, John Edgar, 1872-1938.; Coover, Margaret E.; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931; Stanford University. Board of Trustees.; Stanford University. Department of Psychology. Faculty.; Wilbur, Ray L., (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949; Diaries.; Mediums.; Psychical research.; Psychology, Experimental.; Shorthand.; Women --California.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Correspondence, 1912-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and clippings, 1912-1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Reprints and articles, 1913-1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Diary, Margaret E. Coover, 1907-1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dissertation (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dissertation (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Report on Experimentation upon the Transfer of Improved Conditions of Attention, 1910-11 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation (Bound) (Box 3)
  - M.A. Thesis – “Formal Discipline from the Standpoint of Experimental Psychology,” 1905. (Box 3)